auctionata.com 2016-08-03

# Privacy | Auctionata

### Privacy Policy (as of 09.2014)

_**Important:**_

_**Please note that this website allows you to purchase goods from Auctionata AG or Auctionata, Inc. - a wholly owned US subsidiary of Auctionata AG. Both organizations operate with different Privacy Policies.**_

_**Before any purchase via this website you will have to take notice and have to accept the respective Privacy Policy which apply for your purchase!**_

_**The Privacy Policy below applies for all purchases of goods at auction or via the online shop in which Auctionata, Inc. acts as the seller.**_

_**For all purchases of goods at auction or via the online shop in which Auctionata AG acts as the seller, thisPrivacy Policy applies.**_

_**The transaction details can be determined from information on the lot detail page.**_

Auctionata, Inc. (“Auctionata”) is committed to letting you know how we will collect and use your personally identifiable information. The policies below are applicable to Auctionata’s network of websites, including www.auctionata.com and [magazine.auctionata.com](https://magazine.auctionata.com/), all email newsletters published or distributed by Auctionata, the Auctionata mobile application, and all other interactive features, services, and communications provided by Auctionata (the ”Sites”), however accessed and/or used, that are operated by us, made available by us, or produced and maintained by Auctionata (collectively “Auctionata” or “we”, “us”, or “our”). We have established this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to let you know the kinds of personally identifiable information we may gather during your visit to these Sites, why we gather your information, what we use your personally identifiable information for, when we might disclose your personally identifiable information, and how you can manage your personally identifiable information.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or who may link to us. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third party websites.

**By visiting our Sites, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your continued use of our Sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. If we intend to apply the modifications or amendments to this Privacy Policy retroactively or to personally identifiable information already in our possession, we will provide you with notice of the modifications or amendments and seek your consent for such use.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or do not see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at [usinfo@auctionata.com](mailto:usinfo@auctionata.com) with “PRIVACY POLICY” in the subject line.

**1\. Information collected about you**

We collect two basic types of information from you in conjunction with your use of the Sites: personally identifiable information (“PII”) and non-personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is information that you may supply to us, as described more fully below (e.g., when registering for an account on a Site). Personally identifiable information is any information that can individually identify you and includes, among other things, your name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card, billing and contact information, driver’s license number, social security number, bank account number, and photographic image. Non-personally identifiable information includes information that does not personally identify you, but it may include tracking and usage information about your location, demographics, and use of the Sites and the Internet.

**A. Personally Identifiable Information**

As a general matter, you can browse the Sites without submitting your personally identifiable information to us. However, there are a number of circumstances in which you may supply us with your personally identifiable information. The following lists the most common ways in which we may collect your personally identifiable information:

  * Registration for an account on the Sites. 
  * Request for customer service or other assistance. 
  * Sign up to receive e-mail newsletters or e-mail alerts from us. 
  * Sign up to receive e-mail offers from Auctionata or Auctionata partners. 
  * Participation in surveys, panels, or market research. 
  * Participation in special events and promotions. 
  * Submission of items for valuation and sale on the Sites. 
  * Purchases on the Sites, including subscriptions to Auctionata services. 
  * Submission of a job application. 
  * Entry in contests or sweepstakes. 
  * Participation on social media accounts involving Auctionata, our Sites and our brands. 
  * Participation in communities, chat rooms and comment threads, other fora, and other interactive services. 
  * Submission of user generated content on any part of the Sites that permit it. 
  * Any other place on the Sites where you knowingly volunteer personally identifiable information.​​ 

**B. Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

In addition, when you interact with the Sites, we may collect certain information that does not identify you individually and our servers may automatically keep an activity log of your use of our Sites (“non-personally identifiable information” or “non-PII”). Generally, we collect and store the following categories of non-personally identifiable information:

  * Demographic data such as age, gender, and five digit zip code as part of collecting personally identifiable information. 
  * Neighborhood information. 
  * Device information about your computer, mobile device, or other device that you use to access the Sites. This information may include IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language, and other transactional information. 
  * Usage information about your use of the Sites. This information includes a reading history of the pages you view. We use this information to provide you a more customized experience on the Sites. 
  * Additional “traffic data” such as time of access, date of access, software crash reports, session identification number, access times, and referring website addresses. 
  * Your search terms and search results. 
  * Other information regarding your use of the Sites. 
  * Aggregate data regarding the use of the Sites. 

**C. Collection of Your Source IP Address/Location Information**

We collect and store your device’s source IP address which may disclose the location of your device at the time you access the Sites. Advertisements and certain content may be directed to you as a result of this data.

In addition, in some cases the Sites can deliver content based on your current location if you choose to enable that feature. If you enable that feature, your current location will be stored locally on your device which will be used by the Sites to serve you certain content tied to your location.

**D. Collection of Personally and Non-Personally Identifiable Information From Other Sources**

We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources (including by us from our offline interactions with you) to, among other things, enable us to verify, update and correct the information contained in our database and to better customize your experience on the Sites. We may also collect PII from credit reporting agencies to, for example, determine your creditworthiness, credit score, and credit usage.

**2\. Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies**

To enhance your experience on our Sites and to facilitate the use of certain functions, we use cookies, web beacons or similar technologies. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer or equipment when you visit certain online pages that record your preferences and actions. We use cookies to track use of our Sites and online services. We may also use cookies to monitor traffic, improve the Sites and make it easier and/or relevant for your use.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to disable or reject cookies. If you delete your cookies or if you set your web browser to decline cookies, some features of the Sites may not work or may not work as designed. For more information on cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at www.allaboutcookies.org.

We may also use web beacons or flash cookies. A web beacon or flash cookie (also known as “action tags”, “tracer tags”, or “single-pixel gifs”) is an invisible graphic on a web page that is programmed to collect non-personally identifiable information about your use of a given website. We do not share or provide personally identifiable information we may collect through such web beacons, such as names, e-mail addresses and phone numbers without your express permission.

We may partner with third party advertising companies who may utilize flash or enhanced cookies or web beacons to better provide advertisements about our goods and services that may be of interest to you. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use the Sites. They may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based advertising or other targeted content. These partners do not have access to or use your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other personally identifiable information from us, without your consent. They may, however, use persistent identifiers to anonymously track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond these Sites. Such third parties may, with sufficient data from other sources, be able to personally identify you, unknown to us.

Your browser or device may include “Do Not Track” functionality. Because a “Do Not Track” compliance protocol has not yet been finalized, Auctionata’s information collection and disclosure practices, and the choices that we provide to customers, will continue to operate as described in this Privacy Policy, whether or not a Do Not Track signal is received. To learn more about the use of this information or to choose not to have this information used by our third party advertising partners by opting out, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.

**3\. Children’s information**

The Sites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. Unless otherwise disclosed during collection and with parent or guardian consent, Auctionata does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age, do not provide personally identifiable information to Auctionata without providing us with consent from your parents. If Auctionata discovers that a child under the age of 13 has provided Auctionata with personally identifiable information and we do not have parental consent, Auctionata will immediately delete that child’s information from the Sites. If you believe that Auctionata has been provided with the personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 13 without parental consent, please notify us immediately at [usinfo@auctionata.com](mailto:usinfo@auctionata.com).

**4\. Use of your information**

We use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Sites. We may use your personally and non-personally identifiable information in the following ways:

  * Provide you with the content, products and services you request. 
  * Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you information about features and enhancements on or to our Sites. 
  * Communicate with you about changes to our policies. 
  * Communicate with you about your comment to a story or topic. 
  * Personalize content and experiences on our Sites, including providing you recommendations based on your preferences. 
  * Send you newsletters, offers and promotions for our products and services, third party products and services, or special events by e-mail, text, or other another medium. 
  * Provide you with advertising, including advertising based on your activity on our Sites or activity on third party sites and applications. 
  * Administer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, and surveys. 
  * Optimize or improve our products, services and operations. 
  * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal. 
  * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites and their purchasing patterns. 

We may use the information from one portion of the Sites on other portions of Sites in our network of Sites, all of which are owned and operated by Auctionata, and we may combine information gathered from multiple portions of the Sites into a single customer record. We may also use and/or combine information that we collect off-line or we collect or receive from third party sources to enhance, expand, and check the accuracy of your customer records.

We may use your location information to:

  * Provide you with the products and services you request. 
  * Personalize content and experiences on our Sites, including providing you recommendations based on your preferences. 
  * Personalize your newsletters, offers and promotions for our products and services, third party products and services, or special events. 
  * Personalize the advertising you receive, including advertising based on your activity on our Sites or activity on third party sites and applications. 
  * Optimize or improve our products, services and operations. 
  * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal. 
  * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites and their purchasing patterns. 

**5\. Sharing of your information**

Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose information about your personally identifiable information collected online to any organizations not part of Auctionata or its subsidiaries or related entities, except as described below. Although, as disclosed below, we may provide your information to our agents, affiliates, and partners, in no event will we sell or rent your personally identifiable information as part of a customer list or similar transaction.

**A. Third-Party Agents**

We have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, including, but not limited to, social media integration, marketing, analytics, and fraud protection. These entities may have access to personally identifiable information if needed to perform their functions. If such access is required, the third parties will be contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that personally identifiable information. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Sites.

**B. Information collected through social media sites**

When you interact with any Auctionata property page or account on a social media platform, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, Tumblr, LinkedIn, YouTube, or Pinterest, we may collect the personally identifiable information that you make available to us on that page or account including your account ID or “handle.” However, we will comply with the privacy policies of the corresponding social media platform, and we will only collect and store such personally identifiable information that we are permitted to collect by these social media platforms. If you choose to link or login to your Auctionata account with or through a social networking service, Auctionata and that service may share certain information about you and your activities. With your consent, we also may share information about your activities, including what you view on the Sites. with that social network’s users.

**C. Business Partners and Other Third Parties**

We may share your personally identifiable information with our business partners or co-marketers from time to time. We may also share your personally identifiable information with third parties that provide products and services that we think you may be interested in. Although our treatment of your personally identifiable information is governed by this Privacy Policy, the business partner or third party’s treatment of your personally identifiable information will be governed by the business partner or third party’s privacy policy. You may withdraw your consent to our sharing of your personally identifiable information with business partners and third parties at any time by following the opt-out process described below.

**D. Assignment**

We may change our ownership or corporate organization while providing the Sites. We may also sell certain assets associated with the Sites. As a result, please be aware that in such event we may transfer some or all of your information to an entity acquiring all or part of our assets or to another company with which we have merged. Under such circumstances we would, to the extent possible, require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time. Nevertheless, we cannot promise that an acquiring company or the merged company will have the same privacy practices or treat your information the same as described in this Privacy Policy.

**E. Law Enforcement, Legal Process, and Emergency Situations**

We may also use or disclose personally identifiable information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Sites; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Sites or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents, or the users of the Sites or the public.

**F. Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

We may disclose or share non-personally identifiable information (or other information, other than personally identifiable information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. Among other things, we will disclose non-personally identifiable information to third parties to help us determine how people use parts of the Sites and who our users are so we can improve our Sites. We will also disclose non-personally identifiable information to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Sites.

We are concerned about ensuring the security of your personally identifiable information. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your device to our servers. Personally identifiable information collected by the Sites is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose your personally identifiable information to you. Please understand, however, that while we try our best to safeguard your personally identifiable information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

**7\. Retention**

The time period for which we keep information varies according to what the information is used for. In some cases, there are legal requirements to keep data for a minimum period. Unless there is a specific legal requirement for us to keep the information, we will retain it for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the data was collected or for which it is to be further processed.

**8\. Public areas, chat rooms and comments**

Please remember that any information you share in public areas, such as chat rooms, features of the Sites that have comment sections, or feedback and review sections (“Public Social Features”), becomes public and anyone may take and use that information. Please be careful about what you disclose and do not post any personally identifiable information that you expect to keep private. Please consult the applicable guidelines, if any, for use of our Public Social Features for more information. Auctionata cannot control who views information that you post in public areas of the Sites and is not responsible for how third parties may use or disclose information that you post in public areas of the Sites. 

**9\. Governing Law**

**A. US Law**

The Sites are published in the United States. We attempt to protect the personally identifiable information of all users of the Sites and we attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws to the extent they may apply to the Auctionata services, but the Sites are located and targeted to United States citizens and our policies are directed at compliance with those laws. If you are uncertain whether this Privacy Policy conflicts with the applicable local privacy laws where you are located, you should not submit your personally identifiable information to Auctionata. 

**B. Notice to Non-US Users**

If you are located outside the United States of America, you should be aware that your personally identifiable information will be transferred to the United States of America, the laws of which may be deemed by the your country to have inadequate data protection. If you are located in a country outside the United States of America and voluntarily submit personally identifiable information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/or storage of that information in, the United States of America.

**10\. Opt-Out Provisions**

To opt-out of having your personally identifiable information shared with business partners and third parties by contacting at [usinfo@auctionata.com](mailto:usinfo@auctionata.com).

You may always opt-out of receiving future e-mail marketing messages and newsletters from Auctionata. We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the bottom of the email. You may not opt-out of receiving transactional e-mails related to your account(s) with Auctionata.

If you have an account with the Sites, you may review and change your information by logging into your account and editing your account profile. You may send an email to [usinfo@auctionata.com](mailto:usinfo@auctionata.com) with “ACCESS AND CORRECT INFORMATION” in the subject line to request the correction or deletion any personally identifiable information that you have provided to us. Be advised that we may not be able to delete your personally identifiable information without also deleting your user account. You will not be permitted to examine the personally identifiable information of any other person or entity and may be required to provide us with personally identifiable information to verify your identity prior to accessing any records containing information about you. We may not accommodate a request to change or delete personally identifiable information if we believe doing so would violate any law or legal requirement, or cause the information to be incorrect. 

**12\. Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Auctionata who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of their personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [usinfo@auctionata.com](mailto:usinfo@auctionata.com) specifying that you seek your “California Customer Choice Notice.” Please allow thirty days for a response.

**13\. Changes to this Policy**

As the Sites continue to develop, we may add new services and features to the Sites. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be updated appropriately. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use the Sites in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy. Your continued use of our Sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. We will not, however, materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of personally identifiable information we have previously collected from you without your express consent.

[PDF version of the Privacy Policy for downloading and printing](https://d2c2dsgt13elzw.cloudfront.net/resources/Original/19/4f/348c-5f03-44ae-b201-c9a5162871eb.pdf)
